[opening theme song playing]
BLUE BOX
[thudding]
EPISODE 10
IT'S NOT A GOOD THING
[gasps]
- It's starting to come off.
- [winces]
Just stay in bed and sleep.
[door closes]
[door opens]
[groans]
[exclaims]
How could I possibly sleep after that?!
[birds chirping]
[thermometer beeps]
Thirty-six-point-five degrees.
You're back to full health.
Yeah, guess so.
Then again,
you are looking a bit exhausted.
Are you going to practice?
I gotta.
You can take the day off
for once, you know.
You work so hard, both you and Chinatsu.
Yeah, we do.
[Taiki] How am I not supposed
to be hung up on this?
I need to focus on badminton right now.
Her weight on me.
The smell of her shampoo... the warmth of...
[screams, cries]
That was way out of bounds.
Taiki! Hey, bro!
- You have a stomachache?
- [Taiki exclaims]
If it's got you out here
yodeling like a freak,
then you should just go home.
Nope, I'm all good.
What are you all up to, anyway?
[Haryu] Cleaning the pool.
Our homeroom teacher asked.
The volleyball club is using the gym
for their practice match,
so I'm killing time till it's over.
I'm just doing it 'cause they said
they'd give me extra credit!
[Haryu] Well, you're here.
Why don't you help us out?
Oh, but I was planning on doing
some strength training and-- [gasps]
[sparkling sound]
[gasps softly]
Count me in.
- Careful not to get your socks wet.
- Got it.
It's not like I'm secretly hoping
to stay close to Chinatsu or anything.
I just want to help them clean the pool.
[groans]
[boy] Haryu, I heard you made
the cut for nationals.
What are you doing
wasting your time cleaning a pool?
[Haryu] I don't mind.
They said I can use the pool
if I help them clean it, so.
[laughs] A-ha!
Haryu just wants to work
on his 25-meter sprint!
This guy is off his nut.
He's like a nuclear reactor.
And you two are gonna
come hang out with me.
[both] Huh?
Swimming is great.
It's a full-body workout.
No, I'm out!
Wait! You...
Taiki.
Let me just say...
You have more weaknesses
than just your smash.
What?
INCREASE MY SMASH PRECISION
- INOMATA
- Why does everyone know my goal sheet?
- [Haryu] I mean, it's on the wall.
In the qualifiers,
your match against Yusa,
you started off pretty terrible,
and you could
barely get your feet to move.
He's a first-year, and his skills
will be even better next year.
Don't get down.
It's a waste of time, okay?
[Taiki] You're right. I'm sorry.
I mean, I don't care.
Whether you lose or not in singles
doesn't matter to me.
- [Taiki grunts]
- But then,
if you're too bummed to play well at all...
Huh? Isn't that right, Chii?
Uh... What are you talking about?
We were just saying
how nice the weather is.
Mm. You're totally right. It is.
Yep, sure is.
That was all. Sorry.
[Chinatsu] Mm-hm.
[Taiki sighs]
[Haryu] Hm.
So, um, you made
any progress on that, or what?
[exclaims, trembles]
[Haryu] What is this reaction?
If you don't wanna talk about it,
then we won't.
Hm? Hm. Well...
[Haryu] Hm?
How do I know
if I even have a chance with her?
HE HAS NO CLUE WITH GIRLS
- Yikes.
- Yeah, I know! I have no game whatsoever!
But I was just wondering if there happen
to be any general standards in this area.
[Haryu] This dude is going after Chii?
[Taiki] Like,
if she calls me by a nickname,
or if we're alone together
in the same room.
[Haryu] Depends on the person, man.
Yep, yep, yep. That's what I thought.
I figured there wasn't going to be
a simple answer. I knew that,
- but still...
- Uh... What are you mumbling about?
Yeah, but then again,
we are talking about Chii.
[Taiki] Hm?
[Haryu] She's not weird
around guys at all.
She gets along equally
with guys and girls, you know.
So true.
That being said,
I don't think she'd make physical contact
with someone she's not into.
I think that's an area
where she keeps some separation.
[Taiki gasps softly]
[Taiki] Okay, okay. Relax.
My cooling patch was just coming loose.
There's no deeper meaning behind it.
No point in randomly assuming things.
Don't get your hopes up.
[water splashing]
Cannonball!
Don't jump in, idiot!
It feels great! Get in, Taiki!
I'll pass on this one,
since I just recovered from a cold.
All right, then, Nishida. Let's do this.
Wait, what? What do you mean?
[footsteps approaching]
STORAGE ROOM
Hi, Taiki. Good work out there.
You too, good work.
[Chinatsu] Did they make you
clean everything up?
[Taiki] Yep.
Don't overthink it, Taiki!
Act like a normal human being. Chill out.
[chuckles]
Those no-good upperclassmen, huh?
[gasps softly]
[Taiki] But you know what?
Chinatsu doesn't seem like
she's concerned about it.
Even though we're alone together.
I'll see you.
Oh, but... Um... Wait, Chinatsu!
I want to thank you for yesterday.
Yesterday...
Yeah, my fever's gone now.
Uh. Oh, right. Yesterday.
Yeah, you're welcome.
All right.
Huh?
Uh, Taiki?
[gasps, grunts]
I'm sorry! I was just wondering... uh...
Whe...
Do you know where
I'm supposed to put this here bucket?
- I think up there.
- [gasps]
Oh, right you are! I didn't realize!
Thanks so much.
[chuckles]
I'm gonna head out.
Yeah.
[sighs]
What am I doing?
I need to be more careful. I know that.
Chinatsu, good work.
Thank for your help earlier, even though
it was my job for the PE committee.
- No, no problem. I had fun.
- Huh?
Well, if it isn't
the Yamaguchi-Sato couple!
[Yamaguchi] Come on, don't tease us.
[laughs] Don't be so shy.
Seeing you two so in love is a good thing!
[Yamaguchi] Jeez.
[Nagisa] Yamaguchi has gotten
prettier and prettier
ever since they started dating.
Man, best years of our lives!
[feel-good music playing]
Once you decide you want one,
you'll get a boyfriend in no time,
don't ya think?
Mm. You saying that just made me realize
that I don't really want one.
Basketball is what's up.
Aren't you the same?
Yep. True.
[girls chattering]
[Chinatsu] What's going on
with volleyball?
[Nagisa] Oh, I heard that girl
was transferring schools.
Her grandma got sick or something.
And, they didn't make it
to nationals, either.
It's kinda selfish, but...
I gotta say, I'm glad
you stayed on our team.
Because of you, we are going to nationals.
Well, it wasn't just me.
We should be grateful
to the relative you're living with.
- [chuckles softly]
- You know what, though?
If there was a hot guy
also staying at your relative's house,
by this point,
you might've had a budding romance.
[coughing]
I didn't say anything that crazy.
It's weird to say
something like that out of the blue.
Just think. Living in the same house,
you'd see him all the time
even if you're too busy for dates.
I feel like you'd never be
in a relationship
unless there's someone that close.
Living together with a guy,
you couldn't help but think about him.
It's not as simple as you make it sound.
Huh? You say something?
Oh, no. It was nothing.
- It's dinner time!
- Whoa! That looks good!
- Wow, everything looks delicious!
- [Taiki] I'll take this one!
- Hey there, sir. All good over here?
- You had better eat some vegetables!
Ah! [gulps]
Mighty good!
Chinatsu, for you.
Oh, thank you very much.
It's really lovely
getting to grill out together.
My wife is the queen of the barbecue.
[Yukiko] Here.
You should have some, too, Chinatsu.
Thank you, Yukiko!
[happy music playing]
[chuckles]
Have as much as you'd like.
[Chinatsu] It's really good.
[Taiki] She really does like eating.
Honey, more veggies please!
Coming right up!
I'll help.
Oh, no. Don't worry about it.
I got this covered, go eat.
I want you to think of our house
as your own.
Well, since I am at my own home,
I can't act like a guest, can I?
Huh. That's very mature of you.
I'm sorry.
I guess I was the one being too formal.
Oh. It's fine.
I'm away from home
for my work so much, and...
you and I haven't really gotten
to talk a lot.
Anything bugging you?
Like, my wife's weight loss gadgets
taking up the whole closet,
or how all the sweets Grandpa recommends
are the weird ones.
Not particularly.
- [Taiki's dad] Oh, are you sure?
- [Taiki] Hm?
[Chinatsu] I mean it.
You don't need to be so considerate of me.
Well, I don't know if I agree with you.
We're taking care
of someone else's daughter after all.
It's our job to make sure that
you are comfortable while staying with us.
[gasps softly]
I just made myself sound cool,
but I was hesitant at first,
of having you as a guest here.
But then,
we were talking, and Yukiko said...
[Yukiko] It's our responsibility,
so I'll step up too.
Those two years are going
to be irreplaceable for Chinatsu!
That time will be more important for her
than it will be for us.
If there's a way that we can help her
during that period,
then it's our duty as parents
to give her that.
Those were her words.
Anyway, Yukiko is the decision-maker
of the house, so I follow her lead.
[Chinatsu] He has his emotional moments.
[Taiki's dad] But I realized
that she had a point.
I knew that you had this dream,
so I thought I needed to support you.
But then, you went and actually made it
to nationals, and I'm very proud.
I want to see you make it even further!
- Yes.
- [Taiki] Dad,
Mom needs yakisoba noodles.
Roger that.
[Taiki] I wonder
what they were talking about.
- [Taiki's dad] They're not here.
- What?!
What are we going to do?
Grocery shopping was your job, right?
[Taiki's dad] I thought
that I bought them.
[Taiki] If Mom finds out,
it's gonna be nothing
but brown rice for a month.
[Chinatsu] I'll go pick some up.
There's something I wanted anyway.
What? Uh, okay.
- I'll leave it up to you then.
- Sure thing.
[Taiki] They've gotten closer?
- Why don't you go with her Taiki.
- Huh?
Look. We're not gonna have a young woman
walking on her own in the dark, son.
Yeah, I totally get that, but...
But I don't know how much distance
I should keep from her on the way.
Then...
I can just go on my own.
[Taiki's dad]
That was not the point I was making.
[Chinatsu] Taiki.
[gasps]
Shall we?
Wait, where did Taiki and Chinatsu go?
The two of them went to the store.
Oh, they didn't have to do that.
It's nice that you and her
got to catch up, just the two of you.
I'm blown away by how mature she is
especially since she's just
one year older than Taiki.
That girl certainly has her act together.
Mm. You're right.
She's almost too together.
[pensive music playing]
We didn't forget anything?
SUPERMARKET MIRAHERU
No, I think we got it.
I am halfway through!
Let's head home.
[Taiki] I managed to get by on chitchat
for the first half of this,
but I've run out of things to talk about.
Should I apologize again
for grabbing her arm?
Hmm, but...
I guess...
I shouldn't eat
a popsicle right now, right?
Popsicle?
I really want one,
but then I think of yakisoba...
[Taiki] That's what
you've been thinking about?
There's enough for everyone,
so I should just wait,
and we can have them together.
[laughs]
[Taiki] Chinatsu... Even she has
childish thoughts sometimes.
Here.
It's one of our family rules.
When we have a barbecue,
you can eat whatever you want.
[exclaims]
That's a great rule!
It's my mom's policy.
I'll have one.
Taiki, I think that you
take after your mother.
Huh?
You don't have to make
such a disgusted face, come on.
Listen, I can't say that I'm ecstatic
to hear that I'm similar to my mother.
You aren't?
You're upbeat, energetic, and genuine.
Altogether, you're a lot like her
if you ask me.
Hm. Well, for you,
I feel like you take after your father.
Your mom seemed more easygoing.
Maybe. I'll have to think about it.
Because with my dad, it's always hard
to tell what's going on in his head.
[Taiki] She does take after her dad.
When I mentioned to him that I wanted
to move into your family's house,
I thought he'd be against it,
but he ended up saying
"I see."
That's all he had to say.
Like, I'm sure my mom
had told him about it in advance.
But I was hoping for a bit more than that.
I ended up taking it to mean,
"That's your decision,
so follow through on it."
[chuckles] He's not too good with words.
[vehicle approaching]
[grunts] Watch out!
[Taiki gasps]
[Chinatsu gasps]
Sorry! Uh...
Dang it! I touched her again
without thinking.
Sorry, I should be walking
on the street side anyway.
Taiki...
So about what happened the other day.
The other day?
The day when you spiked a fever.
Let's forget about it.
- [gasps]
- [wind blowing]
[sad music playing]
Honestly, I...
was acting carelessly considering I'm...
living with a guy.
It wasn't a good thing to do,
as someone who's in your family's care.
So, I won't do anything like that again,
going forward.
Let's go.
[Taiki] What?
She just... set a boundary between us.
[door opens]
[Chinatsu] We're back.
[Taiki] And I got the sense that
she's aware of how I feel about her.
She's good.
She was encouraging me to have high hopes.
And then she goes
and draws a line between us.
[music fades]
Okay, everybody,
summer break starts tomorrow...
SUMMER BREAK
...but keep yourselves in check, all right?
Try and aim to do things in moderation,
and make sure--
- [bell chimes]
- [boy 1] Sir, yes, sir!
- [boy 2] Buh-bye, teach!
- [teacher] Now hold on a minute!
[students chattering]
It's summer break, and yet your energy
is really bringing me down.
I get it. You're pissed
about the homework?
- Feel that.
- That's not it.
[Hina] You tryna tell me you're not
against having homework on our break?
No, that's not it either.
[Hina] Thought so.
Ooh, lightbulb moment!
We hole up in the library,
and do it together
after practice Saturday!
[chuckles] Good, right?
And I'm betting
that you wanna copy our answers.
- [Hina whistles]
- [Ito] Um...
[all] Hm?
Would you mind
if we joined in on that too?
- And me, also!
- Yeah, totally!
We'll all go then!
[Ito] Thanks, you're the best.
- Hey, could you help me with my Spanish?
- [Hina] I am loving this!
[Hina] Now we don't have to worry
about homework anymore.
We haven't started yet.
I am so excited!
There are a ton of things
I wanna do over summer break!
Won't you be prepping
for nationals, though?
I mean, I will.
But badminton has practice
almost every day, too, right?
That's right.
[Hina sighs]
- Oh, Chinatsu.
- [Taiki exclaims]
[Hina] She saw us!
- [Kyo] Hm?
- [Hina] Huh?
Why are you hiding down there?
[Taiki groans]
I'm not hiding.
There was a pencil lead on the floor.
You really suck at lying.
[Taiki] It really is nothing.
My family had a barbecue the other day,
and everyone's getting along.
It's just...
We got close to each other, physically,
and, apparently,
she thinks it's not a good thing.
She said that to me and...
I'm just a little confused
on what I'm supposed to do.
[sad piano music playing]
All right. To practice!
SUMMER BREAK
[closing theme song playing]